Downloaded from
YTS.BZ
Official YIFY movies site:
In the beginning,
there was only ocean...
until she emerged.
Our mother island, Te Fiti.
Her heart held the power
to create life itself...
and Te Fiti shared it with the world.
In time,
some sought to capture
the heart for themselves.
For they believed,
if they could possess it,
the power of creation would be theirs.
And one day, the most daring of them all
voyaged across the vast ocean to take it.
He was a demigod of the wind and sea.
Whoo-hoo!
A warrior.
- - A trickster.
Chee Hoo!
- A shape-shifter...
...who could change form
with the power of his magical fish hook.
And his name was Maui.
She was rumbling
before we got here, right?
But without her heart,
Te Fiti began to crumble,
giving birth to a terrible darkness.
Maui tried to escape,
but was confronted by another
who sought the heart.
Te Kā! A demon of earth and fire.
Maui was struck from the sky...
...never to be seen again.
And his magical fish hook
and the heart of Te Fiti
were lost to the sea,
where, even now, a thousand years later,
Te Kā and the demons of the deep
still hunt for the heart.
Hiding in a darkness
that will continue to spread.
Draining the life
from island after island,
until we are all devoured
by the bloodthirsty
inescapable jaws of death!
But one day, the heart will be found
by someone who will journey
beyond our reef,
find Maui,
deliver him across the great ocean
to restore the heart of Te Fiti
and save us all.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Thank you, Mother.
- Papa.
- There she is.
As you all know,
no one goes beyond the reef.
We are safe here.
There is no darkness,
and there are no monsters.
Monsters!
I said there are no monsters.
As long as we stay
on our very safe island,
we'll be fine.
The legends are true, Son.
Don't worry. I'll help you.
Shoo! Shoo, shoo!
Leave him alone.
Wanna go to the ocean?
Yeah, me too.
Whoa!
Moana!
Moana.
Moana, we don't go out there.
It's dangerous.
Moana, listen.
There is nothing beyond the reef
but storms and rough seas.
- Moana.
- Mom's here.
There's my little adventurer.
You are very important, sweetheart,
and the next great chief of our people.
And you will do wondrous things.
Can I do them in the water?
No.
Never pass the reef.
Come on.
First, you must learn
where you're meant to be.
Ah!
♪ Moana! Make way! Make way! ♪
♪ Moana, it's time you knew ♪
♪ The village of Motunui is all you need ♪
Heihei.
♪ The dancers are practicing! ♪
♪ They dance to an ancient song ♪
♪ Who needs a new song? ♪
♪ This old one's all we need ♪
♪ This tradition is our mission ♪
♪ And, Moana, there's so much to do! ♪
♪ Don't trip on the taro root
That's all you need ♪
♪ We share everything we make ♪
♪ We make ♪
♪ We joke and we weave our baskets ♪
♪ The fishermen come back from the sea ♪
♪ I wanna see ♪
♪ Don't walk away ♪
♪ Moana, stay on the ground now ♪
Our people will need a chief and ♪
- ♪ There you are ♪
♪ There comes a day ♪
♪ When you're gonna look around ♪
♪ And realize happiness is ♪
♪ Where you are ♪
- ♪ Consider the coconut! ♪
- ♪ The what? ♪
♪ Consider its tree ♪
♪ Use each part of the coconut
It's all we need ♪
♪ We make our nets from the fibers ♪
♪The water is sweet inside ♪
♪ We use the leaves to build fires ♪
♪ And cook up the meat inside ♪
♪ Consider the coconuts!
The trunks and the leaves! ♪
♪ The island gives us what we need ♪
♪ And no one leaves ♪
♪ That's right, we stay ♪
♪ We're safe and we're well-provided ♪
♪ And when we look to the future ♪
♪ There you are ♪
♪ She'll be okay ♪
♪ In time, she'll learn just as I did ♪
♪ You must find happiness
Right where you are ♪
♪ I like to dance with the water ♪
♪ The undertow and the waves ♪
♪The water is mischievous, ha!
I like how it misbehaves ♪
♪ Some people may think I'm crazy ♪
♪ Or say that I drift too far ♪
♪ But once you know what you like ♪
♪ Well, there you are ♪
♪ You are your father's daughter ♪
♪ Stubbornness and pride ♪
♪ Mind what he says but remember
You may hear a voice inside ♪
♪ And if that voice starts to whisper ♪
♪ To follow the farthest star ♪
♪ Moana, that voice inside
Is who you are ♪
Moana.
Dad. I wasn't gonna go out there.
Just doing my daily canoe inspections.
Walk with me.
I wanted to bring you here
since the moment you opened your eyes.
This is a sacred place.
A place of chiefs.
Soon you will come of age,
and place a stone
on this mountain like I did.
Like my father did.
And his mother did.
And every chief that has ever been.
And on that day,
when you add your stone...
you will raise this whole island higher.
You are the future of our people, Moana.
And our people are not out there.
They're right here.
It's time to start preparing
to be who they need you to be.
♪ We make our nets from the fibers ♪
♪ We weave our nets from the fibers ♪
♪ A real tasty treat inside ♪
♪We sing these songs in our choirs ♪
♪ We have mouths to feed inside ♪
♪ The village believes in us ♪
♪ That's right ♪
♪ The village believes ♪
♪ The island gives us what we need ♪
♪ And no one leaves ♪
♪ So here I'll stay ♪
♪ My home, my people beside me ♪
♪ And when I think of tomorrow
There we are ♪
♪ I'll lead the way ♪
♪ I'll have my people to guide me ♪
♪ We'll build our future
Together, where we are ♪
♪ 'Cause every path leads you back to ♪
♪ Where you are ♪
♪ You can find happiness
Right where you are ♪
♪ Where you are
Where you are ♪
Chee Hoo!
Yeah, yeah. Pull it.
Pull it tight.
Careful, Heihei. Stay.
- Pua!
Thank you very much.
We need to review the meaning
of the word "stay."
All right.
Let's give this stone thing a try, Pua.
This one says "passionate."
Which grove?
Over there.
It's getting worse.
We should clear any diseased trees.
Replant. Let us know if you find more.
"Leader of the people."
This is "playful, but fierce."
It's important, Pua.
It's forever.
None of those boats have fish.
We checked everywhere.
- I looked over there.
- We need to let the chief...
What's wrong?
It's not just the coconuts
now, it's also the catch.
We've tried the whole lagoon.
There are no fish.
They are just gone.
I remember when my grandmother was chief.
A hurricane kept the fish away for weeks.
But they had dried fish stores
and fresh coconuts.
They were prepared to wait
until the fish came back.
And they did come back.
But there is no hurricane.
And even then, the lagoon was never empty.
There's always a solution.
We just need to look for it.
Ow!
If the lagoon is empty,
what if... what if we fish farther out?
Beyond the reef.
No one goes beyond the reef.
But if we can't rely on coconuts
- and the fish here are gone...
- Moana.
...and we're surrounded by a whole ocean.
We have one rule.
- A rule when there was food.
- A rule that keeps us safe.
We have to do something.
I will not endanger our people
so you can run back to the water.
Moana.
I thought I'd find you here.
I didn't say we should go beyond the reef
because I wanna be on the ocean.
I know.
But you kind of do.
I am trying to be what our people need.
What he needs.
But it doesn't seem to be enough for him.
He was just like you, Moana.
- Dad?
- Mm-hmm.
Drawn to the ocean.
Ignoring the warning,
"Don't cross the reef."
He took a canoe...
-
...crossed the reef,
and found an unforgiving sea.
Waves like mountains.
His cousin begged to be on that boat.
Your dad couldn't save him.
He's hoping he can save you.
Sometimes who we wish we were
and who we need to be,
they don't match up.
-
♪ I've been staring
At the edge of the water ♪
♪ Long as I can remember ♪
♪ Never really knowing why ♪
♪ I wish I could be the perfect daughter ♪
♪ But I come back to the water
No matter how hard I try ♪
♪ Every turn I take, every trail I track ♪
♪ Every path I make
Every road leads back ♪
♪ To the place I know where I cannot go ♪
♪ Where I long to be ♪
♪ See the line
Where the sky meets the sea ♪
♪ It calls me ♪
♪ And no one knows how far it goes ♪
♪ If the wind in my sail on the sea ♪
♪ Stays behind me ♪
♪ One day I'll know ♪
♪ If I go there's just no telling ♪
♪ How far I'll go ♪
♪ I know everybody on this island ♪
♪ Seems so happy on this island ♪
♪ Everything is by design ♪
♪ I know everybody on this island ♪
♪ Has a role on this island ♪
♪ So maybe I can roll with mine ♪
♪ I can lead with pride
I can make us strong ♪
♪ I'll be satisfied if I play along ♪
♪ But the voice inside
Sings a different song ♪
♪ What is wrong with me? ♪
♪ See the light as it shines on the sea ♪
♪ It's blinding ♪
♪ But no one knows how deep it goes ♪
♪ And it seems like
It's calling out to me ♪
♪ So come find me ♪
♪ And let me know ♪
♪ What's beyond that line?
Will I cross that line? ♪
♪ The line where the sky meets the sea ♪
♪ It calls me ♪
♪ And no one knows how far it goes ♪
♪ If the wind in my sail on the sea ♪
♪ Stays behind me ♪
♪ One day I'll know ♪
♪ How far I'll go ♪
-
It's okay. It's okay. We're okay.
I can do this.
There's more fish beyond the reef.
There's more beyond the reef.
Okay, okay. Steady.
Not bad.
-
Hold on.
Pua!
No! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
-
Whatever just happened,
blame it on the pig.
Ooh...
Let me see.
Are you gonna tell Dad?
I'm his mom.
I don't have to tell him anything.
He was right.
I don't belong out there.
I need to put my stone on the mountain.
Okay. Have fun.
You're not gonna try
and talk me out of it?
You said it's what you want.
It is.
When I die,
I'm going to come back as one of these.
Whoo!
Or I chose the wrong tattoo.
Why are you acting weird?
I'm the village crazy lady. That's my job.
Gramma, if there's something
you wanna tell me,
just tell me.
Is there something you wanna tell me?
Is there something you want to hear?
Did this mountain get taller?
You've been told
all of our people's stories
but one.
What is this place?
Do you really think our ancestors
stayed within the reef?
What's in there?
The answer to the question
you keep asking yourself.
Go inside, bang the drum,
and find out...
"Who am I meant to be?"
"Bang the drum."
-
♪ We are sailors ♪
♪ Invited ♪
♪ By the god of the great sea
It comes ♪
♪ Take the challenge
It's good ♪
♪ Also ♪
♪ Oh! Oh! ♪
♪ Lean forward ♪
- Chee Hoo!
- ♪ The bird that touches the cloth ♪
♪ Oh! Oh! ♪
♪ Te mundu, te malai ♪
♪ It's not for the family ♪
♪ We read the wind and the sky
When the sun is high ♪
♪ We sail the length of the seas ♪
♪ On the ocean breeze ♪
♪ At night we name every star ♪
♪ We know where we are ♪
♪ We know who we are
Who we are ♪
♪ Away, away! ♪
♪ We set a course to find ♪
♪ A brand-new island everywhere we roam ♪
♪ Away, away! ♪
♪ We keep our island in our mind ♪
♪ And when it's time to find home ♪
♪ We know the way ♪
♪ Away, away! ♪
♪ We are explorers reading every sign ♪
♪ We tell the stories of our elders ♪
♪ In a never-ending chain ♪
♪ Auē! Auē! ♪
♪ Te fenua, te mālie ♪
♪ Nae ko hākilia ♪
♪ We know the way ♪
We were voyagers?
We were voyagers!
Gramma! I have a lot of questions!
Why did we stop?
Maui.
When he stole the heart of Te Fiti,
an evil began.
Te Kā awoke.
Monsters emerged
and canoes stopped coming back.
To protect our people,
the ancient chiefs forbid voyaging.
For so long,
we have forgotten who we are.
And now,
the darkness has finally found us.
It's everywhere.
The island is dying.
The stories are true.
The story has just begun.
I saw you that day, Moana,
in the water.
I thought it was a dream.
The ocean chose you
to journey beyond our reef.
- Find Maui,
deliver him across the great ocean
to restore the heart of Te Fiti...
...and save us all.
Our ancestors believe
that Maui lies there
at the bottom of his fish hook.
Follow it and you will find him.
Dad needs to know.
I'll show him the canoes.
He will help.
Do what you must, but hurry.
Hurry.
We tried the whole lagoon.
The crops are turning black!
What will we do
if the fish don't come back?
Now the taro
is withering too.
Panicking will not feed any...
Please.
I know how we can fix this.
We can find Maui. I have the heart.
If we follow the stars,
the hook... There's canoes.
Dad, we were voyagers once.
We can voyage again.
You think you're the first one
that Gramma's taken to that place?
You knew?
Our ancestors closed that cave
for a reason.
They were trying to protect us.
No. Dad, you told me to help our people.
Ignoring who we are
isn't helping our people.
We have to find Maui, restore the heart.
Our island is dying. We can't do nothing.
This is nothing.
Chief! It's your mother!
- What can be done?
- Nothing we can do.
Go.
Not now. I can't.
You must.
The ocean chose you.
Follow the fish hook.
And when you find Maui,
you grab him by the ear
and you say,
"I am Moana of Motunui.
You will board my boat,
sail across the sea
and restore the heart of Te Fiti."
I can't leave you.
There is nowhere you can go
that I won't be with you.
Go.
♪ There's a line
Where the sky meets the sea ♪
♪ And it calls me ♪
♪ But no one knows ♪
♪ How far it goes ♪
♪ All the time wond'ring
Where I need to be ♪
♪ Is behind me ♪
♪ I'm on my own ♪
♪ To worlds unknown ♪
♪ Every turn I take, every trail I track ♪
♪ Is a choice I make
Now I can't turn back ♪
♪ From the great unknown
Where I go alone ♪
♪ Where I long to be... ♪
♪ See her light up the night in the sea ♪
♪ She calls me ♪
♪ And yes, I know ♪
♪ That I can go... ♪
♪ There's a moon in the sky
And the wind is behind me ♪
♪ And soon I'll know ♪
♪ How far I'll go ♪
I am Moana of Motunui.
You will board my boat,
sail across the sea
and restore the heart of Te Fiti.
I am Moana of Motunui.
You will board my boat, sail a...
- Uh...
Heihei!
-
See?
See, you're all right. Look.
The ocean is a friend of mine.
Heihei.
Please tell me you brought your own food.
I am Moana of Motunui.
You will board my boat,
sail across the sea
and restore the heart of Te Fiti.
No, no, no, no, no, no. No, no.
Come on!
I am Moana of Motunui.
You will board my boat...
What?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
It's okay, Heihei. Just a little rain. Ah!
Ocean, please, help me!
Come on.
No!
Um, what? I said, "Help me."
And this?
Wrecking my boat? Not helping!
Fish pee in you all day.
And worse stuff too, so...
Maui?
Maui.
Maui, demigod of the wind and sea...
...I am Moana of Motunui.
You'll board...
No. You will board my boat.
Yeah. You will board my...
Boat!
The gods have given me a boat.
And a tiny little human.
Well, hello, tiny human.
Not too sure why they thought
I needed you.
You can take back the little human.
Oh. I'm gonna eat whatever that is.
It's a chicken. His name is Heihei.
His name is "yum-yum"
when he goes in my tum-tum.
- Maui.
- Mm-hmm.
- Shape-shifter.
- Mmm.
- Demigod of the wind and sea.
- Yes.
- I am Moana of Motunui--
- Mmm. Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Hero of men.
- Huh?
So it goes like this.
Maui, shape-shifter,
demigod of the wind and sea,
hero of men.
Ah! Women. Women too. Men and women.
Not a girl-guy thing. Men and women.
Maui is a hero to all.
I think you're doing great.
Start at the top.
Three, two, one... hit it.
I am Mot... I am... I...
- I am Moa...
- No, no.
You're completely overwhelmed.
But don't worry. Maui always
has time for his fans.
- Oh, I'm...
- That's okay.
May I see the oar? Thank you. All right.
You know, before I write anything,
I wanna know about you.
Tell me your hopes, tell me your dreams.
Well, I guess I kind of jumped the--
Time's up. I gotta bounce.
"To Moana.
Figure out your dreams and follow them."
- Oh.
The chicken just pecked my foot.
He wants one too.
"Oar-tograph" for chicken.
Look at that face.
I know it's not every day you get a chance
to see your hero in person.
You are not my hero.
And I'm not here so you can sign my oar.
I'm here because you stole this,
the heart of Te Fiti.
And you will board my boat,
sail across the sea and put it back.
Yeah.
You know, it's kind of crazy
because it almost sounds like
you don't like me.
Which is impossible, 'cause look at me.
I've been stranded
on this island
for over a thousand years,
'cause I was trying to get that heart
as a gift for you mortals.
So, what I believe
you are trying to say...
- ...is, "I appreciate you."
- What?
- "I'm grateful for you."
- Huh?
That's all right.
I'll stop messing with you.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- No, no, I-I didn't...
- I wasn't... I didn't...
- Mmm.
I wasn't saying...
Okay, okay.
♪ I see what's happening
Yeah ♪
♪ You're face to face with greatness ♪
♪ And it's strange ♪
♪ You don't even know how you feel ♪
♪ It's adorable ♪
♪ Well, it's nice to see
That humans never change ♪
♪ Open your eyes
Let's begin ♪
♪ Yes, it's really me ♪
♪ It's Maui, breathe it in ♪
♪ I know it's a lot, the hair, the bod ♪
♪When you're staring at a demigod ♪
♪ What can I say except
You're welcome? ♪
♪ For the tides, the sun, the sky? ♪
♪ Hey, it's okay, it's okay
You're welcome ♪
♪ I'm just an ordinary demiguy ♪
♪ Hey
What has two thumbs ♪
♪ And pulled up the sky ♪
♪ While you were waddling
Yea high? ♪
♪ This guy ♪
♪ When the nights got cold ♪
♪ Who stole you fire from down below? ♪
♪ You're lookin' at him, yo ♪
♪ Oh, also I lassoed the sun
You're welcome ♪
♪ To stretch your days and bring you fun ♪
♪ Also I harnessed the breeze
You're welcome ♪
♪ To fill your sails
And shake your trees ♪
♪ So what can I say except
You're welcome? ♪
♪ For the islands I pulled from the sea ♪
♪ There's no need to pray
It's okay ♪
♪ You're welcome. Ha! ♪
♪ I guess that's just my way of being me ♪
♪ You're welcome ♪
♪ Well, come to think of it ♪
♪ Kid, honestly, I could go on and on ♪
♪ I can explain every natural phenomenon ♪
♪ The tide? The grass? The ground? ♪
♪ Oh, that was Maui just messing around ♪
♪ I killed an eel
I buried its guts ♪
♪ Sprouted a tree
Now you've got coconuts ♪
♪ What's the lesson?
What is the takeaway? ♪
♪ Don't mess with Maui
When he's on a breakaway ♪
♪ And the tapestry here on my skin ♪
♪ Is a map of the vict'ries I win! ♪
♪ Look where I've been
I make everything happen! ♪
♪ Look at that mean Mini-Maui
Just tickety-tappin' ♪
♪ Singin' and scrappin'
Flippin' and snappin' ♪
♪ Ooh, is she clappin'?
Victory lappin' ♪
♪ Bringin' the chorus back in ♪
♪ Well, anyway, let me say ♪
- ♪ You're welcome ♪
♪ For the wonderful world you know ♪
♪ Hey, it's okay, it's okay ♪
- ♪ You're welcome ♪
♪ Well, come to think of it I gotta go ♪
♪ Hey, it's your day to say
You're welcome ♪
♪ You're welcome ♪
♪ Cuz I'm gonna need that boat ♪
- ♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
- ♪ I'm sailing away, away ♪
- ♪ You're welcome ♪
♪ Cuz Maui can do anything but float ♪
♪ You're welcome ♪
And thank you!
Hey!
You lying, sneaking, son of a...
Beach, I'll smell you later.
♪ Cuz I'm gonna need that boat ♪
-
Ow! What?
I'm not gonna go to Te Fiti with some kid.
I'm going to get my hook.
Buddy, you already have yours.
I'm not Maui without mine.
And if you keep it up,
I got a cave for you to go in.
Boat snack.
That's what I remember.
Ow!
She's fine.
Look, she's gonna have
an entire island to herself.
And she's gonna love it.
And I'm gonna love you.
In ma belly.
Let's fatten you up, drumstick.
Wow, you are dumb.
Good chicken.
- Huh?
Oh, my...
Ah. So close.
I could watch that all day.
- Enjoy the island.
Maui, out.
Hey, no!
You have to restore the heart.
Bye-bye.
Hey! Hey!
The kid? No, haven't seen her.
-
And she's back. Close your eyes.
I am Moana of Motun--
Are you kidding?
Good job, me.
It was Moana, right? Of, um...
Motunui.
Restore the heart.
-
- Ah. Oh!
I'll take my chances with the monsters.
All right, I'm out.
I thought we were friends.
What's wrong with you?
There's nothing wrong with me.
I'm awesome. Haven't you heard?
- Are you...
- No.
No, no, no. Don't do that.
- Afraid of it?
- No, no, no.
No, no. Afraid? Maui? No.
I don't do fear.
That thing is not a heart, it's a curse.
And the second I took it,
I got blown out of the sky
and I lost my hook.
Get it away from me!
- Get this away?
- Yes, that's enough!
I am a demigod...
and I will smite you,
and you don't want any of this smote.
- Who? Me?
- Yeah, you.
Just like you don't want that.
That thing doesn't create life,
it's a beacon of death
and if you don't put it away,
then bad things are gonna happen.
- Put this away?
- Yes.
- The heart of Te Fiti.
- Don't do that. Stop that!
The heart of Te Fiti.
Don't tempt the gods that way,
you're gonna get us killed.
I'm gonna get us to Te Fiti
so you can put it back.
Thank you. You're welcome.
Oh.
You know, if I were wrong just once,
I would be humble. I promise.
What is that?
Kakamora.
- Kakamora?
- Kakamora.
Poisonous little pillagers.
They look kinda cute.
Really? Define "cute."
And I wonder what they're here for.
Tighten the halyard. Take up the stays.
You can't sail?
I am self-taught.
- Oh.
- Whoa!
-
Can't you shape-shift or something?
No magic hook, no magic powers.
-
- No! Get off!
- Oh!
No, no, no, no, no.
Heihei!
-
Give it back!
Maui, they took the heart!
We have to get it back.
Maui!
-
I told you it was cursed.
All right!
There! It's right there!
You're turning?
- What are you doing?
- Escaping.
- The heart is that way.
- We'll never get it.
Okay, I'll do it.
Hey, what am I gonna steer with?
They're just gonna kill ya!
I'm gonna need that heart.
Going up!
Whoa!
-
Got it.
Come on, come on, come on.
Yeah! Whoo-hoo!
That was incredible! We did it!
We? By "we" you mean Maui,
because we didn't do anything. I did it.
And by the way, Maui's not
spelled with a "we,"
it's spelled with an "I."
We are alive.
But I'm still not taking that thing back.
Why not?
'Cause in order to get to Te Fiti
you gotta go through Te Kā,
a lava monster.
You ever defeat a lava monster, princess?
No. Have you?
You know what,
I'm just gonna say it.
You both are very bad...
at worshiping me.
You want me to believe
that of your entire island,
your chief, he picked you?
Picked is a strong word.
I'm not going on a suicide mission
with some mortal.
In order to restore the heart,
you need me, and me says no.
- But I just--
- I'm getting my hook.
End of discussion.
You'd be a hero again.
That's what you're all about, right?
Little girl. I am a hero.
Well, maybe you were,
but a lot's changed in a thousand years.
Now you're the guy who
stole the heart of Te Fiti,
the guy who cursed the whole world.
You're no one's hero.
That's impossible. I am everyone's hero.
Oh, nice. Just gang up on the demigod.
Look, I promise,
you put this back, save the world,
you'd be everyone's hero.
Forever. Sounds good, right?
Maui, Maui, Maui.
You're so amazing. Wow.
Look at the definition in his curls.
It's true, I do have beautiful hair.
If I do this, then you and your people
will address me as hero.
Act like one and I might.
Deal.
You can't get rid of me.
Worth a shot.
I guess you're coming.
Okay, to the lair of Tamatoa.
If anyone has my hook,
it's that beady-eyed scavenger.
You could teach me sailing.
This isn't sailing, princess.
It's called wayfinding.
It's about seeing where
you're going in your mind.
It's about knowing where you are
from knowing where you've been.
I'm not a princess.
I'm the daughter of the chief.
It's the same thing.
- No.
- Yes.
If you wear a skirt
and if you have a little animal sidekick,
you're a princess, princess.
You're not a wayfinder.
Unless you can find a way
to be less annoying.
Really?
Blow dart to my butt cheek?
-
If you can talk, you can teach.
I am a demigod.
Wayfinding. Lesson one. Hit it.
Slack out the tricing.
No. Not that one.
The other one.
No. The brown rope.
You're measuring the stars,
not giving the sky a high five.
If you feel the water and it's warm,
it means we're going the right way.
It's cold.
Wait, it's getting warmer.
Ew!
That's disgusting. What is wrong with you?
Chee Hoo.
We're here.
Moana.
Dad?
- Moana, where are you?
- Mom?
Moana!
Go.
Help!
Muscle up, buttercup.
We're here.
You sure this guy's got your hook?
Tamatoa is not a guy.
Anything that's cool
that sinks to the bottom of
the ocean, he collects it.
There's nothing cooler than my hook...
except maybe my face...
or these muscles.
I'm getting my hook.
You start singing now,
I'm gonna throw up everywhere.
So, not seeing an entrance.
The entrance will only appear
after the human sacrifice.
Kidding.
You need to lighten up.
Oh, wow.
Oh, yeah.
Don't worry,
it's a lot farther down
than it looks.
Chee Hoo!
I'm still falling.
This is crazy.
The ocean chose you for a reason.
Guess what?
Still falling.
I can do this. Chee Hoo!
You lived. Go you.
How's my hair look? Don't answer that.
You know what,
maybe you could jump back up
and get out of here while
the grown folks go to work.
Stop trying to ditch me.
I can do stuff.
Yeah? Like what?
Like I just jumped
into that monster mouth thing
and I didn't die.
And I got you off that island.
- Wha--
- No one else did that.
Hmm.
So, what's our plan?
Oh, you're still here.
I was planning on doing it all alone.
But I'm not that lucky today.
Maui.
I can be useful if you'd let me.
- Okay.
- Really?
You know, sometimes in life
you're the hero
and sometimes...
...you're the bait.
Wait, what?
Wow, a shiny, glittery cave.
Sparkle, sparkle.
What, are you going to a funeral?
Do you know how unconvincing
you sound right now?
You have to commit.
Say the other line that I wrote.
Have fun with it. You got it.
Wow!
I'm a sparkly treasure. Look over here!
Do it again, but more convincing.
Sparkle.
- Sideways.
- Sparkle.
- Smarter.
- Sparkle?
- You're butchering the line.
- Sparkle!
You sound like a drunk.
I don't even know what that was.
- Sparkle!
- Way too unlikeable.
Sparkle.
Mm-mmm. It all sucks.
- I can't do this anymore.
- Yes, you can.
You be the bait.
I'm just gonna go up there and get it.
You go up there, you're gonna get killed.
At least this would be over.
Okay, listen. If you run into him,
you have to distract him.
And remember, he loves to brag
about how great he is.
Oh. You two must get along well.
Not really.
Not since I ripped off his leg.
You ripped off his...
Maui.
-
That's curious.
Shell head, shell body.
Wait a minute, you're a human.
Ew.
What are you doing down here
in the realm of monsters?
Pick an eye, babe.
I can't... I can't concentrate
on what I'm saying if you...
Yeah, pick one. Just pick one.
You're a funny-looking thing.
But this necklace...
Don't! That's my gramma's.
Oh, "That's my gramma's."
Well, I ate my grandma, and it took a week
'cause she was absolutely humongous.
Why are you here?
Oh.
What?
Uh, for you!
'Cause you're so amazing. To meet you.
Go on.
We mortals have heard a lot about
the crab who ate his nana
and became a legend.
Wait a minute.
Are you just trying to get me
to talk about myself?
Because if you are,
- I will gladly do so!
- Huh?
In song form!
Okay, everyone. This is why we rehearse.
Lights. Music.
Let's hit it.
♪ Well, Tamatoa
Hasn't always been this glam ♪
♪ I was a drab little crab once ♪
♪ Now I know I can be happy as a clam ♪
♪ Because I'm beautiful, baby ♪
♪ Did your granny say
"Listen to your heart"? ♪
♪ "Be who you are on the inside"? ♪
♪ I need three words
To tear her argument apart ♪
♪ Your granny lied ♪
♪ I'd rather be shiny ♪
♪ Not a blemish on the surface
Not a speck ♪
♪ Double check ♪
♪ Is ev'rything shiny? ♪
♪ I will sparkle
Like a wealthy woman's neck ♪
♪ Just a sec ♪
♪ Don't-cha know
♪ Fish are dumb, dumb, dumb ♪
♪ They chase anything that shimmers ♪
- ♪ Beginners, oh ♪
♪ And here they come, come, come
To the brightest thing that glimmers ♪
♪ Fish dinners... ♪
♪ I just love free food ♪
♪ And you look like seafood ♪
No! Whoa! No, no, no! Whoa!
- Yummy!
- Crab cake!
I'm back.
- It's Maui time!
What do you say, little buddy? Giant hawk?
Comin' up.
Chee Hoo!
-
Yes, I'm holding it right.
I know what I'm doing.
I didn't order cala-Maui.
Whoa!
♪ Well, well, well ♪
♪ Little Maui's having trouble
With his look ♪
Maui!
♪ Ya little semi-demi-mini-god! ♪
♪ Ouch
What a terrible performance ♪
♪ Get the hook!
Get it? ♪
♪ You don't swing it
Like you used to, man ♪
♪ Yet I have to give you
Credit for my start ♪
♪ And your tattoos on the outside ♪
♪ For just like you
♪ I've made myself a work of art ♪
♪ I'll never hide
I can't, I'm too shiny! ♪
♪ Watch me dazzle
Like a diamond in the rough ♪
♪ Strut my stuff
My stuff is so shiny ♪
♪ Send your armies
But they'll never be enough ♪
♪ My shell's too tough
Maui man ♪
♪ You can try, try, try ♪
♪ But you can't expect a demigod
To beat a decapod ♪
♪ Look it up ♪
♪ You will die, die, die ♪
♪ Now it's time for me to take apart ♪
♪ Your aching heart ♪
♪ Far from the ones who abandoned you ♪
♪ Chasing the love of these humans ♪
♪ Who made you feel wanted ♪
♪ You tried to be tough ♪
♪ But your armor's
Just not hard enough ♪
♪ Maui, and now it's time
To kick your heinie ♪
♪ Ever seen someone so shiny... ♪
♪ Soak it in cuz it's the last
You'll ever see ♪
♪ C'est la vie, mon ami
I'm so shiny ♪
♪ Now I eat you
So prepare your final plea ♪
♪ Just for me ♪
♪ You'll never be quite as shiny ♪
♪ You wish you were nice 'n' shiny ♪
- Hey!
- Huh?
I got something shiny for ya.
The heart of Te Fiti.
Don't give it to him, kid.
You want it? Come and get it.
You can't run from me.
Oh, you can. You keep surprising me.
There's only so far you can
get on those two little legs.
- You tripped.
Bad luck. -
Oh, the power of creation
for a crustacean.
Oh. Where is it? Where is it?
-
Come on, Te Fiti.
Time to go. Shall we?
- What about the heart?
- He can have it.
I've got a better one.
Yes! It is mine! It's...
Wait a minute.
I see, she's taken a barnacle
and she's covered it
in bioluminescent algae
as a diversion.
- Come back here!
- Over there!
There is no escape.
- And jump!
- Chee Hoo!
Oh, there is one escape.
Hey, did you like the song?
Did you have any notes or feedback?
-
Maui. Maui.
Ma--
Listen, I, uh, really appreciate
what you did down there.
That took guts. And I...
Oh. I get it.
Big, tough, handsome guy gets emotional.
And what do you do? You laugh in his face.
It's just you... you got this like...
Oh, no. Is there something on my face?
In my teeth? Is there
something in my teeth?
No, no. No, no, no. Shark head.
I-I like this part. I mean...
I mean the nice part.
I-I was not making fun
of the shark portion.
Look, the point is you did me a solid.
But you almost died.
And I couldn't even beat the dumb crab.
So, chances of beating Te Kā
are bubkes.
This mission has no chance
because you're still you
and I have a shark head.
♪ Hey, it's okay, it's okay ♪
♪ There's no wind ♪
♪ We're dead soon
We're dead soon ♪
♪ 'Cause we're both gonna die
On this boat, hey ♪
Maybe try it with a smile.
Giant hawk.
-
♪ Maui's gonna do
The dead man's float, hey ♪
Why are you being like this?
Leave me alone.
Both of you, leave me alone.
How do you get your tattoos?
They just show up... when I earn 'em.
They just show up.
How did you get that one?
That one's man's discovery of Nunya.
- What's Nunya?
- Nunya business.
- I'm just gonna keep asking.
- Drop it.
Why was that crab poking at it?
- Back off.
- What is it?
- No.
I don't want to talk about it.
Give it back!
If you don't want to talk, that's fine.
But my island, my people...
my family...
they won't survive if we don't make it.
I want to help.
If you let me.
I wasn't born a demigod.
I had human parents.
Who decided they didn't want me.
So they threw me in the ocean,
like I was nothing.
Somehow, I washed ashore.
Found by the gods.
They gave me my hook.
They made me Maui.
So back to the humans I went.
I gave them everything.
Islands,
fire,
coconuts.
I gave them anything they ever wanted.
You took the heart for us.
You did everything for us.
So we'd love you.
Yes.
It was never enough.
The ocean chose you too.
That's your takeaway?
Because it saw someone
worthy of being saved.
And what am I now?
You're Maui.
The gods didn't make that true.
You did.
Okay.
Not in front of the guest.
The wind.
Maui, it's back.
Sorry, chicken.
-
Chee Hoo.
I figured it out.
You know, the ocean would love
when I would pull up the islands.
Your ancestors would voyage
her seas and find them.
That necklace you're wearing,
that belonged to Tautaivasa,
the first master wayfinder.
He knew no two voyages were the same.
Different every time.
A true wayfinder...
will see all the water... as a bridge...
and not a barrier.
And if I were the ocean,
I couldn't find a better curly-haired,
sidekick-having non-princess...
...to start voyaging again.
That is the nicest thing
you've ever said to me.
Probably should've saved it for Te Fiti.
I did.
- Moana, if I don't--
- You can do this.
You're Maui.
That's true.
It's Maui time.
Go save the world.
Chee Hoo!
Maui!
Maui.
We need to pull back. Now!
- What are you doing?
- Finding you a way in.
Now's our chance.
- Turn around.
- No.
- We're not gonna make it.
- Yes, we will.
- Moana, stop!
- No! I can do it.
Are you okay?
Maui?
I told you to turn back.
- I thought we could make it.
- "We"?
I thought I could make it.
I'll find a way to fix your hook.
The gods made my hook.
You can't fix it.
Next time I'll be more careful.
- There's no next time.
- But now we know
Te Kā can't follow us
into the water.
We can find another way around.
There is no other way. I'm not going back.
Take a look at my hook.
One more hit and it's over.
But my people, my island...
Without my hook,
I am nothing.
We're only here 'cause you stole the heart
in the first place.
No.
We're here
because the ocean told you
that you were special.
And you believed it.
- I am Moana of Motunui.
- Goodbye, Moana.
You will sail across the sea
and restore the heart...
I'm not killing myself so you can prove
you're something you're not.
The ocean chose me! It chose us!
It chose wrong.
- Goodbye, Moana.
- Maui!
-
Maui, no! Don't go!
Maui?
Ocean, why did you bring me here?
I was never the right person.
You should choose someone else.
Please.
You're a long ways past the reef.
Gramma.
I guess I chose the right tattoo.
I tried, Gramma, but...
I couldn't do it.
I can't do it.
If you're ready to go home,
I will be with you.
Why do you hesitate?
I don't know.
♪ I know a girl from an island ♪
♪ She stands apart from the crowd ♪
♪ She loves the sea and her people ♪
♪ She makes her whole family proud ♪
♪ Sometimes the world seems against you ♪
♪ The journey may leave a scar ♪
♪ But scars can heal and reveal ♪
♪ Just where you are... ♪
♪ The people you love will change you ♪
♪ The things you have learned
Will guide you ♪
♪ And nothing on earth can silence ♪
♪ The quiet voice still inside you ♪
♪ And when that voice starts to whisper ♪
♪ "Moana, you've come so far" ♪
♪ Moana, listen... ♪
♪ Do you know who you are? ♪
Who am I?
♪ I am a girl who loves my island ♪
♪ And the girl who loves the sea ♪
♪ It calls me ♪
♪ I am the daughter of the village chief ♪
♪ We are descended from voyagers ♪
♪ Who found their way across the world ♪
♪ They call me ♪
♪ I've delivered us to where we are ♪
♪ I have journeyed farther ♪
♪ I am everything I've learned and more ♪
♪ Still it calls me ♪
♪ And the call isn't out there at all ♪
♪ It's inside me ♪
♪ It's like the tide ♪
♪ Always falling and rising ♪
♪ I will carry you here in my heart ♪
♪ You remind me ♪
♪ That come what may ♪
♪ I know the way ♪
♪ I am Moana! ♪
I am Moana of Motunui.
- You will board my boat...
- ...board my boat...
- ...sail across the sea...
and restore the heart of Te Fiti.
We have to lure Te Kā away
and slip past,
'cause it can't follow us
through the water to Te Fiti.
None of which you understand
because you are a chicken.
All right, Te Kā.
Try and catch me.
Come on!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Heihei.
Nice work.
Te Fiti.
-
You came back.
I never should've left.
But your hook...
- One more hit...
- Te Kā's gotta catch me first.
Maui.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Let's do this.
Hey, Te Kā!
Bring it on!
Chee Hoo!
Yes!
Moana!
Oh, no.
Te Fiti?
She's gone.
-
Te Kā!
Tau male loto!
Tau male fatu!
Tau male mana!
Tau mole ola!
- Taui'a!
-
The ocean chose you.
Let her come to me.
♪ I have crossed the horizon to find you ♪
♪ I know your name ♪
♪ They have stolen the heart
From inside you ♪
♪ But this does not define you ♪
♪ This is not who you are ♪
♪ You know who you are ♪
Who you truly are.
Te Fiti.
Chicken lives.
I think.
Your hook.
Hook or no hook,
I'm still Maui.
Hey.
Te Fiti!
How ya been? It's me, Maui.
We met back in the... Uh... Hmm... Mm-mmm.
What I think he's trying to say...
What I did was wrong
and I clearly have a lot... a lot of stuff
that I need to work out from my past.
Issues, things like that.
I'm just a humble demigod
trying to find his...
It's no excuse.
I am sorry.
Truly.
Go ahead.
It would be rude to refuse
a gift from a goddess.
I'm back, baby.
Chee Hoo Hoo Hoo...
Who am I?
Right now, I am grateful.
Thank you.
I'm gonna miss you, drumstick.
You know, Motunui is that way.
You should come visit.
I would love to.
Well, we'd be happy to have you. Anytime.
Plus, my people could use
a master wayfinder.
They already have one.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I'll see you out there, Moana.
See you out there.
Chee Hoo!
Tui.
Moana.
Mom! Dad!
I may have gone
a little ways past the reef.
I'm so proud of you.
- Pua!
Okay, okay. Yes, next time you can come.
Moana of Motunui,
you raise our whole island higher
and take every one of our people
and ancestors farther.
Sei e va’ai maia
manaia o le tatou olaga.
Sei e va’ai maia manaia o le tatou olaga.
♪ Away! Away!
We set a course to find ♪
♪ A brand new island everywhere we roam ♪
♪ Away! Away! ♪
♪ We keep our island in our mind ♪
♪ And when it's time to find home
We know the way ♪
♪ Away! Away! ♪
♪ We are explorers reading every sign ♪
♪ We tell the stories of our elders ♪
♪ In a never-ending chain ♪
♪ Auē! Auē! ♪
♪ Te fenua te malie ♪
♪ Nae ko hakilia ♪
♪ We know the way ♪
♪ You're on your way
You're on the ocean ♪
♪ You're flying towards
An undiscovered shore ♪
♪ This ocean spray, the wind in motion ♪
♪ You know that no one's
Been this way before ♪
♪ And off you go ♪
♪ With nothing but the wind
And sky to guide you ♪
♪ Don't you know ♪
♪ Your ancestors are with you
Right beside you ♪
♪ I'm right beside you
I'm right beside you ♪
♪ Find your way, your horizon ♪
♪ Find solace on the surface of the sea ♪
♪ Race the day, find your island ♪
♪ You're answering the call
And you are free ♪
♪ When you're lost in the rain ♪
♪ The tides are high
And all the skies are gray ♪
♪ Find your strength
Find that voice inside ♪
♪ Remind yourself
And find yourself along the way ♪
- ♪ Along the way ♪
♪ Along the way ♪
♪ Along the way, along the way ♪
♪ We're on our own ♪
- ♪ Our destination ♪
♪ Seems hopeless
But we know we've gotta try ♪
♪ Seems hopeless but we know... ♪
♪ We're not alone
Each constellation ♪
♪ Is holding its position in the sky ♪
♪ And every star ♪
♪ Keeps shining in the distance
When we need 'em ♪
- ♪ Here we are ♪
♪ We're finally on our way ♪
♪ And it feels like freedom ♪
♪ It feels like freedom ♪
♪ Find your way, your horizon ♪
♪ Find solace on the surface of the sea ♪
♪ Race the day, find your island ♪
♪ You're answering the call
And you are free ♪
♪ When you're lost in the rain ♪
♪ The tides are high
And all the skies are gray ♪
♪ Find your strength
Find that voice inside ♪
♪ Remind yourself
And find yourself along the way ♪
- ♪ Along the way ♪
♪ Along the way ♪
♪ Chee Hoo! ♪
♪ Moana ♪
♪ How many steps to the mountaintop? ♪
♪ How do you get to the summit? ♪
♪ No looking down
Cuz that's how you drop ♪
♪ You second-guess and you plummet ♪
♪ But from it you learn to get up
Dust yourself off, you're still alive ♪
♪ One foot in front of the other, Moana ♪
♪ You wanna stay on it until you arrive ♪
♪ Your legs are tired ♪
♪ Your lungs are sore ♪
♪ You're far away from
What you hunger for ♪
♪ You fall back, you'll stumble forward ♪
♪ And beyond that ♪
♪ You're runnin' towards something new ♪
♪ Some nights you're fighting
The lightning and thunder ♪
♪ And wondering what to do ♪
♪ But remember the voyagers
Who came before you ♪
♪ They struggled and made it through ♪
♪ And the people who follow
The trail you blaze ♪
♪ Will get there because of you ♪
- ♪ Hey, hey ♪
- ♪ Hey ♪
♪ I'm with you along the way ♪
♪ When you're lonely along the way ♪
♪ I will guide you ♪
♪ Along the way ♪
♪ Right beside the voice inside you ♪
♪ Find your way ♪
♪ Your horizon ♪
♪ Find solace on the surface of the sea ♪
♪ Race the day, find your island ♪
♪ You're answering the call
And you are free ♪
♪ When you're lost in the rain ♪
♪ The tides are high
And all the skies are gray ♪
♪ Find your strength ♪
♪ Find that voice inside ♪
♪ Remind yourself
And find yourself along the way ♪
- ♪ Along the way ♪
-  ♪ Along the way ♪
♪ Along the way ♪
- ♪ Along the way ♪
♪ Chee Hoo! ♪